aota.org 2017-06-24

# Privacy Policy - AOTA

Effective December 22, 2016

## Introduction

This Privacy Policy describes AOTA’s practices regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of the information we collect from and about you when you use any of AOTA’s websites and mobile applications (the “Service”). From time to time the number of websites that make up the Service may change. Each website that makes up the Service will provide a link to this unifying privacy policy. As such, this policy will govern the privacy practices of each website that links to this policy.

AOTA respects the privacy of its members and website visitors. We aim to give our website visitors the opportunity to know what information we collect about them, why we collect that information, how we use that information to improve their experience, and how they can limit the use of that personally identifiable information (PII) beyond the purposes for which they first provided it. 

By accessing or using the Service, you agree to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use.

## Policy Changes

Whenever we change our policy, we will post those changes on this page. We will also announce these changes on the AOTA.org website. Since these policy change notices last only a limited time, you should periodically check this privacy policy to review any possible changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## Data We Collect

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

Log Files & Analytics

Our servers and other devices automatically record certain information. These logs may include information such as the resource you requested, your IP address, your browser type and its settings, the URL of the site you visited to get to our site (referrer), the last page you visited on our site, all of the URLs you viewed while on the Service, search terms used, number of clicks, scroll depth, files downloaded, date and time, and other such information. This information helps AOTA improve the efficiency, security, and relevance of the Service.

Device Identifiers

When using the Service on a mobile device, AOTA collects specific device information contained in your “device identifier.” Such information includes the device type, operating system, and mobile network. We may associate this identifier with your account to customize the Service to your devices/account.

Location Information

Likewise, use of the Service on a mobile device may result in collection of the location of the device. This information may also be associated with your account. You can disable this on your particular device. However, be aware that some features of the Service may not function properly as a result.

**Personally Identifiable Information**

If you create an account on the Service, at a minimum, we collect the following personal information: 

  * First name
  * Last name
  * Email address

You may also provide us with additional/optional information such as your role in OT, your work setting, your phone number(s), and mailing and billing addresses, special needs, educational information, and other demographic information. Your name and email address, in conjunction with any additional/optional information you associate with your account, is referred to herein as your “Profile Information.”

If you elect to purchase any type of product or offering sold on the Service, including but not limited to memberships, event registrations, books, magazine articles, and/or educational courses, we will utilize a third party credit card payment processing company to collect payment information, including your payment information, billing address, and phone number. We will share this information with the third party credit card processing company as described in the section “How We Use & Share Your Data: Trusted Service Providers and Business Partners.” We do not store your credit card information while using the Service for a purchase.

## How We Use & Share Your Data

**Use As Directed By You**

We will display your Profile Information on your profile page and elsewhere on the Service in accordance with the preferences you set. To review and revise specific profile information, such as phone numbers, email addresses, and mailing and billing addresses, go to: <http://myaota.aota.org/>.

**Trusted Service Providers and Business Partners**

We may use third party service providers to help us deliver, improve, protect, or promote the Service. We may use various third parties to deliver online coursework, deliver online publication content, send email messages and updates, analyze the security and operation of the Service, process payments, and other similar services. Using these third party service providers may also result in sharing and storing your personally identifiable information in locations and on servers, or clouds outside of the direct control of AOTA.

From time to time, these third party service providers may have access to your personally identifiable information for the limited purpose of providing the contracted service. ****

**With Law Enforcement or In Order to Protect Our Rights**

We may disclose your aggregated and personally identifiable information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. In order to comply with law or regulation; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect AOTA’s rights or property, and as AOTA deems appropriate in its sole discretion, we may also disclose your aggregated or personally identifiable information to government authorities, law enforcement authorities, or our legal counsel. 

**In an Aggregate and Non–Personally Identifiable Manner**

AOTA may share aggregated non–personally identifiable information with third parties, including without limitation its partners, advertisers, and other interested third parties as it deems appropriate in its sole discretion to help them understand or improve the Service.

**Children’s Privacy**

Our Service is not directed to persons under 13. AOTA does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register for an account on the Service. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at website@aota.org.

**Cookies**

AOTA uses cookies to provide, monitor, analyze, and improve the Service. We use cookies to remember your user name when you return to the Service. We can also use Cookies to control access to AOTA member-only content, to streamline authentication and navigation on the Service. In the future, AOTA may add additional cookies and pixel tags/web beacons to further support the Service.

**Google Analytics Cookies**

AOTA uses cookies on the Service to support our Google Analytics service. Google Analytics is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to help AOTA analyze how users use the Service, in an effort to further improve the Service. 

**Google Advertising and Interest-Based Reporting**

AOTA also uses Google Analytics Advertising and Interest Reporting on the Service. This allows us to know more about our visitors to the Service such as gender, age range, and broad interest categories. 

**Google Remarketing Campaigns**

AOTA uses Google’s Remarketing, which allows us to show you advertising relevant to AOTA on other websites that are part of the Google Display Network.

Simply stated, remarketing allows us and Google to do the following:

  * Advertise to you across other websites on the Google Display Network
  * Show you ads on other sites you may visit, and those ads will be tailored based on past visits to AOTA’s web properties.

**Disabling Cookies/Advertising and Remarketing Opt-Out**

You may disable or block cookies on your web browser; however be aware that some features of the Service may not function properly.

Alternatively you can opt out of the Google Analytics Advertising Features using a browser plug-in. To do so, please go to: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

To read Google’s Data and Privacy practices, go to: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>

To tailor your Remarketing campaign settings, go to Google’s Ads Settings: <http://www.google.com/settings/ads>

**Use of IP address**

Every computer and device connected to the Internet is assigned an Internet Protocol (IP) address. IP addresses are typically assigned in country-based blocks and can often be used to identify the country, state, and city from which a computer is connecting to the Internet. Because IP addresses need to be used by websites for the Internet to function, AOTA websites have access to your IP addresses.

## Privacy Controls

You may modify certain preferences related to your account. Specifically, you can opt out of email newsletters, AOTA membership offers, AOTA products, AOTA events, AOTA advocacy efforts, information from third-party vendors, and surveys. 

## Data Integrity & Security

AOTA applies commercially reasonable and industry-standard technical, administrative, and organizational security measures to protect the integrity of the data we collect and to guard against unauthorized or unlawful access to, use of, or accidental destruction of such data.

Particularly, when you enter sensitive information (such as credit card numbers) as part of our Service, we encrypt the transmission of that information using industry-standard encryption.

## Risks Inherent in Sharing Information

Although we take reasonable steps to maintain the security of our systems and the information associated with your account, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you share your Content, and we are not responsible for third-party circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures on the Service.

## Do Not Track Signals

Some browsers have a “do not track” feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. We currently do not respond to “do not track” signals.

## Links to Other Websites

The Service contains links to other websites not operated by AOTA. We are not responsible for the practices employed by such websites nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, this Privacy Policy is no longer in effect and your activities on that third party website are subject to such third party website’s own rules and policies. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Service and to read the privacy policies of those websites.

## Contact Us

For questions about these or any of AOTA’s terms or policies, email us at [website@aota.org](mailto:website@aota.org).

Last Updated: 12/22/2016
